<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>speps.fr - Rémi Gillig</title>
    <link>http://speps.fr/</link>
    <description>Recent content on speps.fr - Rémi Gillig</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 19:46:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://speps.fr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Torus Trooper - Rebooting a 15 year-old game written in D - Part 1 Compiling</title>
      <link>http://speps.fr/articles/torus-trooper-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 19:46:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://speps.fr/articles/torus-trooper-part1/</guid>
      <description>See also
 Part 1 - Compiling a new executable Part 2 - Running the game for the first time Part 3 - Making it cross platform  While exploring D recently, I remembered a game I played while at university 15 years ago. For a long time, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t remember the name at all, only that it was from a Japanese developer. After some search wrangling, I finally managed to find the name of the game: Torus Trooper!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Torus Trooper - Rebooting a 15 year-old game written in D - Part 2 Running</title>
      <link>http://speps.fr/articles/torus-trooper-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 19:46:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://speps.fr/articles/torus-trooper-part2/</guid>
      <description>See also
 Part 1 - Compiling a new executable Part 2 - Running the game for the first time Part 3 - Making it cross platform  From part 1, we stopped after successfully compiling a new executable, but will it run?
Answer is&amp;hellip; NO!
Alright, let&amp;rsquo;s dig into it!
D1&amp;rsquo;s std.file.listdir core.exception.RangeError@src\abagames\tt\barrage.d(110): Range violation ---------------- 0x00448944 in _d_newarrayU 0x0041734B in void abagames.tt.barrage.Barrage.addBml(immutable(char)[], immutable(char)[], float, bool, float) D1 used to have a function named listdir in Phobos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup Hugo with Travis CI and GitHub Pages</title>
      <link>http://speps.fr/articles/hugo-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 11:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://speps.fr/articles/hugo-setup/</guid>
      <description>This article aims to introduce and show how to generate your Hugo site on Travis CI and then deploy it automatically to GitHub Pages.
Have your Hugo website ready The first step is to have your Hugo website working locally at least. It should build without errors. The default output folder is public. NOTE: if you changed that using publishdir in your config file please change it in the following steps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Profile</title>
      <link>http://speps.fr/profile/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 16:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://speps.fr/profile/</guid>
      <description>My name is Rémi Gillig, I am a video game tools software engineer.
I like C++, C# and making tools for everyone. It has a great impact on the projects and usually involves a number of other disciplines.
I am also interested in procedural generation and rendering and I like to follow the advances in these areas through SIGGRAPH and GDC talks, lectures and research papers.
I&amp;rsquo;m currently working at Rare Ltd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ATI Overscan Fix</title>
      <link>http://speps.fr/ati-overscan-fix/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 19:22:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://speps.fr/ati-overscan-fix/</guid>
      <description>ATI Overscan Fix What is overscan ? ATI (recently AMD) has an option called &amp;ldquo;Overscan&amp;rdquo;, it allows you to adjust the scaling of the content of the screen to compensate the cropping done on some screens (TV screens mostly).
What&amp;rsquo;s the problem ? Unfortunately, the driver setting for this is by default set at 15% which means everytime you install a new driver it gets reset and you need to go to the settings and &amp;ldquo;fix&amp;rdquo; it by hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesomium.NET</title>
      <link>http://speps.fr/awesomiumdotnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 19:22:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://speps.fr/awesomiumdotnet/</guid>
      <description>Awesomium.NET Disclaimer This project is not supported anymore, it&amp;rsquo;s only provided now as an example on how to interface C++ and .NET code together (a lot of Marshal inside).
In the meantime, you can see an alternative to Awesomium here : EA STL. It also contains the famous http://www.open-std.org/jtc1/sc22/wg21/docs/papers/2007/n2271.html which is a C++ STL which aims for performance and video games.
What is Awesomium? Awesomium (by Adam Simmons) is a C++ library which uses the Windows port of WebKit created by the Google Chrome team also known as Chromium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PaperPlane</title>
      <link>http://speps.fr/paperplane/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 19:21:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://speps.fr/paperplane/</guid>
      <description>PaperPlane Update : This project has won the student prize prize at Milthon Awards 2010 ex-aequo with Gerridae.
PaperPlane is a project made during my second year at ENJMIN. It involved a team of 9 persons during 6 months. It was an incredible experience.
The goal of the game is to remember childhood memories by unlocking figments of a child imagination. You explore and fly around these memories with a paper airplane.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AttracTouch</title>
      <link>http://speps.fr/attractouch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 19:21:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://speps.fr/attractouch/</guid>
      <description>AttracTouch Update : This project has won the &amp;ldquo;Best Use of Technology&amp;rdquo; prize at e-magiciens 2009.
AttracTouch is a project made during my first year at ENJMIN. It involved a team of 6 persons during 3 months. I personally invested time and money for building myself a multitouch screen (see image on the side) using resources at NUI Group.
The principle of the game is to use your fingers to lead particles from the launcher to the receiver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>e-magiciens 2009</title>
      <link>http://speps.fr/emagiciens2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 19:16:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://speps.fr/emagiciens2009/</guid>
      <description>e-magiciens 2009 e-magiciens is a festival about interactivity, animation and video games. You can have more information on their website : http://www.e-createurs.net/emagiciens/accueil.php.
Prizes for video games  SACD / e-magiciens : Blind Trust - ENJMIN Game Design, offered par Ubisoft : [[puddle|Puddle]] - ENJMIN Auteurs SACD / GDC : Abstrakt - ENJMIN, One’s - Supinfogame Best Sound Design, offered by CNAM : Muse - ENJMIN Best Graphics, offered FMX festival : Caïman Songe - Emilie Cohl Most Original Use of Technology, offered by Cap Digital : AttracTouch - ENJMIN  Pictures </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puddle</title>
      <link>http://speps.fr/puddle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 18:59:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://speps.fr/puddle/</guid>
      <description>Puddle Update : This project has won the &amp;ldquo;Game Design&amp;rdquo; prize at e-magiciens 2009.
Update : This project is a finalist at the IGF Student competition : http://www.igf.com/10studentfinalists.html.
Puddle is a project made during my first year at ENJMIN. It involved a team of 6 persons during 3 months.
The principle of the game is to tilt the world to make your liquid move through it by gravity. You have to reach the end of the level with enough liquid to go to the next one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>http://speps.fr/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 18:57:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://speps.fr/resume/</guid>
      <description>Resume For my most up-to-date stuff checkout my LinkedIn.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>http://speps.fr/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 18:51:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://speps.fr/projects/</guid>
      <description>Active Projects  LibTessDotNet, C# port of the GLU tessellator XInput.NET, XInput plugin for Unity  Personal Game Projects  PaperPlane (2010), paper airplane video game Puddle (2009), video game with a fluid AttracTouch (2009), multitouch puzzle game Paper Tetris (2007), computer version of a game I played at university  Discontinued Projects  Awesomium.NET (2010), WebKit for .NET, useful for GUIs ATI Overscan Fix, (2012), fixes overscan issues on ATI/AMD drivers in the registry  Events  e-magiciens 2009, festival with video games  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links</title>
      <link>http://speps.fr/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 18:48:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://speps.fr/links/</guid>
      <description>Links Friends  Vincent Pancaldi, programmer Pierre Lemasson, graphics designer Laurent Martin, sound designer Ronan Kergosien, graphics designer Stéphane Noyer, programmer  Programming  Stack Overflow, most useful website of all time Wolfgang Engel, blog on Graphics Shawn Hargreaves, blog on various topics Coding Horror, insightful blog AIGameDev, AI in video games Smashing Magazine, web design and web programming Programming for Video Gamers, thanks to Dylan for this one!  Comics  xkcd Cyanide &amp;amp; Happiness The Perry Bible Fellowship Saturday Morning Breakfast Cereal The Adventures of Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>http://speps.fr/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 18:41:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://speps.fr/home/</guid>
      <description>Headline Puddle is now out on XBLA/PSN (published by Konami), more information at http://puddle-game.com.
Welcome! I hope you will find interesting things here as I try to update its content with what I&amp;rsquo;m interested in.
If it&amp;rsquo;s your first time here, I suggest visiting my introduction page which contains some information about myself and my life. Otherwise, you can feel free to use the menu to navigate through the different sections and explore this website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://speps.fr/aboutme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 10:20:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://speps.fr/aboutme/</guid>
      <description>About Me My name is Rémi Gillig, I was born in France and I studied video games programming at ENJMIN.
My passion for programming began some time ago and I spent most of my education learning programming. At first, I had the chance to have access at home to early computers and wrote some basic programs using GW-BASIC. For the record, it looks like this :
1 2  10INPUT&amp;#34;WHAT IS YOUR NAME&amp;#34;;N$ 20PRINT&amp;#34;HELLO &amp;#34;N$&amp;#34; :)&amp;#34;   This is awesome for a 6 year-old boy and when you discover the power of IF/THEN/ELSE and GOTO you can achieve pretty much anything, right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging a DirectX memory leak</title>
      <link>http://speps.fr/articles/directx-refcount/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 21:31:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://speps.fr/articles/directx-refcount/</guid>
      <description>A short tale (with pictures and code) of a recent debugging session.
DirectX uses reference counting to handle the destruction of its resources. When creating a resource, the handle returned by DirectX already has a reference counter of 1. When this resource is not needed anymore, you call Release, each call decrements the reference counter by 1. However, the memory allocated by DirectX for this resource will only be released when the reference counter reaches 0.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>